Gertrude Edna Lewis Gates papers, 1903-1935.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Gertrude Edna Lewis Gates papers, 1903-1935.
AZ 007
Gates, Gertrude Edna Lewis.
Correspondence, notebooks, cattle records, and financial papers pertaining to the operation and maintenance of the D.A. Ranch and of rental property in Flagstaff.
1.25 linear feet.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
none.
Biographical Note
Arizona rancher; operated the DA Ranch, 1910-1922, in Cornville, AZ, Yavapai County.
Organization
This collection is organized into 3 series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1902-1934.
Series 2: Financial Records, 1908-1935.
Series 3: Cattle and ranching records, 1907-1935.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, notebooks, cattle records, and financial papers pertaining to the operation and maintenance of the D.A. Ranch and of rental property in Flagstaff. Includes detailed descriptions of the ranch and inventories of equipment. Also included are personal letters, many relating to Gates' interest in missionary work among Indians.
Access Terms
DA Ranch (Cornville, Ariz.)
Cattle trade -- Arizona -- History -- Sources.
Ranch life -- Arizona.
Indians of North America -- Missions -- Arizona.
Ranches -- Arizona -- Records and correspondence.
Women ranchers -- Arizona.
Container List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1902-1934.
  - Correspondence (DA Ranch). 1911-1934. (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence, Possible sale to United Society of Christian Endeavor. 1919-1925. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Personal: family, friends, missionary interests, Indian wards, misc. 1902-1933. (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondance, Banks. 1906-1928. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Financial Records, 1908-1935.
  - Check Stubs, Miscellaneous Financial Notes. 1917-1929. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bills and Receipts. 1908-1935. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Taxes and Assessments. 1929-1934. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cattle Records: Sales, brands, stud book. no date. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Other Business Interests. 1902-1919. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Cattle and ranching records, 1907-1935.
  - Grazing Permits. 1925-1935. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - DA Ranch, Advertisement. no date. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - DA Ranch, Description. no date. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Legal Papers, Leases. no date. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Clippings. no date. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Notes and Memos, relating to ranch operations. 1907-1940. (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Advertising and Business Cards. no date. (Box 3, Folder 7)